Register of the Survey of Race Relations records
Hoover Institution Archives
- Major Documents, 1905-1926 (Boxes 24-32)
  - "Life History of a Japanese," by Cornelia C. Rhodes (Box-folder 30: 285)
    3 pages; Life histories, Americanization, Intermarriage; Japanese; Southern California
  - "Rufugio B.'s Story," by Irma Weill (Box-folder 30: 286)
    3 pages; Life histories, Heritages; Mexican; Southern California
  - "Nellie F.'s Story," by Irma Weill (Box-folder 30: 287)
    3 pages; Life histories, Americanization; Chinese; Southern California
  - "Life History of Mr. and Mrs. F.," by Amanda M. Chase (Box-folder 30: 288)
    2 pages; Life histories, Americanization, Competition and land; Japanese; Southern California
  - "Present Estimated Japanese Population in Los Angeles City and County," by Masao Dodo, University of Southern California, Los Angeles (Box-folder 30: 289)
    4 pages; Population, Communities; Japanese; Southern California
  - "What Magazines Do the Japanese Read?" by Masao Dodo, University of Southern California, Los Angeles (Box-folder 30: 290)
    7 pages; Americanization, Communities; Japanese; Southern California
  - "Life History of Philippine Student," by Norma R. Holmes (Box-folder 30: 291)
    3 pages; Americanization, Life histories; Filipino; Southern California)c
  - "Life History of a Mexican," by Norma R. Holmes (Box-folder 30: 292)
    3 pages; Life histories, Americanization, Competition and land; Mexican; Southern California
  - Autobiography of Luke Chess, perhaps the only autobiography of a Chinese in the United States (Box-folder 30: 293)
    26 pages; Life histories, Race consciousness; Chinese; Northern California
  - General summary of the Oriental situation in Californian agriculture (Box-folder 30: 294)
    12 pages; Competition and land: Agriculture; Japanese; Northern California; Chinese; Southern California; and Hindus
  - "Language Handicap in the Rural Districts," by Ruth Wadsworth Quire (Box-folder 30: 295)
    7 pages; Americanization, Race consciousness, Life histories; Japanese; Seattle
  - Life history of Kazuo Kawai, Los Angeles (Box-folder 30: 296)
    1925 March 2 (20 pages; Life histories, Americanization, Race consciousness; Japanese; Southern California
  - Interview with representatives of produce companies in Los Angeles regarding the effect of the Alien Land Law on the small fruit and vegetable business, by Chloe Holt, 1925 February 27 (Box-folder 30: 297)
    13 pages; Competition and land; Japanese; Southern California
  - A group of 13 interviews with individuals of Los Angeles Chinatown, by Catharine Holt (Box-folder 30: 298)
    57 pages; Americanization, Communities; Chinese; Southern California
  - "Interview with Chiyoe Sumi," student, Lincoln High School, Los Angeles, by Catharine Holt, 1925 February 21 (Box-folder 30: 299)
    5 pages; Life histories, Americanization; Japanese; Southern California
  - "Interview with Mrs. Yamada," by Catharine Holt, 1924 May 26 (Box-folder 30: 300)
    3 pages; Life histories, Race consciousness; Japanese; Southern California
  - "A Study of the Japanese Fisherman at Curtis Packing Company in Long Beach," by William Kinchelve, University of Southern California (Box-folder 30: 301)
    7 pages; Competition and land; Japanese; Southern California
  - "Interview with R. Kado," owner, Sunnyland Nursery, Los Angeles, by Claude Williams (Box-folder 30: 302)
    5 pages; Competition and land, Racial traits, Goodwill; Japanese; Southern California
  - "Life History of Paul Hiratzaka," by Robert E. Park and William C. Smith, Los Angeles, California (Box-folder 30: 303)
    8 pages; Life histories, Americanization; Japanese; Southern California
  - "Autobiography," by Adelaide K--- (Box-folder 30: 304)
    3 pages; Life histories, Americanization; Korean; Southern California
  - "Juan, the Story of a Filipino Boy," by Helen P. Beattie, Highland, San Bernardino County, California (Box-folder 30: 305)
    13 pages; Americanization, Goodwill, Racial traits, Intermarriage; Filipino; Southern California
  - "Interview with Attorney Robert Young of Hollywood," by William C. Smith, 1925 March 14 (Box-folder 30: 306)
    2 pages; Goodwill, Race consciousness; Japanese; Southern California
  - Digital copy of Box 31
  - Letter of warning from Sei Fujii, Los Angeles, translated from Japanese (Box-folder 31: 307)
    2 pages; Americanization; Japanese; Southern California
  - Letter to George Gleason from Karl C. Darlington, 1924 February 15 (Box-folder 31: 308)
    5 pages; Goodwill, Americanization; Japanese; Southern California
  - Life history of a Japanese college freshman girl (Box-folder 31: 309)
    15 pages; Life histories, Race consciousness, Americanization; Japanese; Southern California
  - "The Life History of a Hawaiian-Born Chinese girl, F--- L---," by William C. Smith (Box-folder 31: 310)
    14 pages; Americanization, Life histories, Race consciousness; Chinese; Southern California
  - "Life History of Henry Shimonouchi," by William C. Smith (Box-folder 31: 311)
    3 pages; Life histories, Race consciousness, Americanization; Japanese; Southern California
  - "Interview with Miss Kyo Inouye," Japanese girl, age 18, Los Angeles, California, by Catharine Holt, 1925 January 16 (Box-folder 31: 312)
    5 pages; Americanization, Race consciousness; Japanese; Southern California
  - "Interview with Miss Chiyo Otera," freshman, University of California, Southern Branch, by Catharine Holt, 1925 February 17 (Box-folder 31: 313)
  - "Interview with Hida Watanabe," Los Angeles, California, by Catharine Holt, 1925 February 9 (Box-folder 31: 314)
    5 pages; Life histories, Race consciousness; Japanese; Southern California
  - "Interview with Mr. and Mrs. William S. Yip," Los Angeles, California, by Catharine Holt, 1925 January 13 (Box-folder 31: 315)
    4 pages; Race consciousness, Americanization; Chinese; Southern California
  - "Interview with Teru Miyamoto," graduate, Los Angeles High School, Los Angeles, California, by Catharine Holt, 1925 January 10 (Box-folder 31: 316)
  - "Interview with Miss Esther B. Bartlett of the Y.W.C.A. International Institute," Los Angeles, California, by Catharine Holt, 1924 December 17 (Box-folder 31: 317)
    6 pages; Americanization; Japanese and Chinese; Southern California
  - "Interview with K-- K--" (name not to be used), Japanese girl, graduate of high school and employed at --- bank, California, by Catharine Holt, 1924 December 20 and 27 (Box-folder 31: 318)
    4 pages; Americanization, Life histories, Race consciousness; Japanese; Southern California
  - "Interview with H. Otsubo," by William C. Smith, Los Angeles (Box-folder 31: 319)
    6 pages; Americanization; Japanese; Southern California
  - "Interview with Iseri," by William C. Smith, 1925 March 4 (Box-folder 31: 320)
    4 pages; Americanization, Race consciousness; Japanese; Southern California
  - Life history of K--- M--- (Box-folder 31: 321)
  - Life history of H--- K--- (Box-folder 31: 322)
    13 pages; Americanization, Race consciousness; Japanese; Southern California
  - Documents relating to Japanese, Limoneira Ranch, Santa Paula, California (Box-folder 31: 323)
    20 documents; 48 pages; Americanization, Life histories, Race consciousness; Japanese; Southern California
  - Questionnaire dealing with agricultural conditions on the Limoneira Ranch, Santa Paula, California (Box-folder 31: 324)
    14 pages; Competition and land; Japanese; Southern California
  - Statement issued by the Joint Committee, composed of representatives of the four state organizations – American Legion, State Federation of Labor, State Grange and Native Sons of the Golden West (Box-folder 31: 325)
    2 pages; Communities; Japanese; Northern and Southern California
  - Statement by J. M. Campbell, principal of one of the schools in the city of Victoria, British Columbia, made in a letter to Professor T. H. Boggs, 1925 May 28 (Box-folder 31: 326)
    4 pages; Americanization; Japanese and Chinese; British Columbia
  - Public opinion of the Oriental in San Jose, California (Box-folder 31: 327)
    10 pages; Americanization, Racial traits, Communities, Competition and land; Japanese and Chinese; Northern California
  - Statement by William C. Allen regarding schools in the vicinity of San Jose in the midst of a large foreign population, 1925 May 9 (Box-folder 31: 328)
    5 pages; Americanization; Japanese and Chinese; Northern California
  - Questionnaire dealing with the public schools of Stockton, San Joaquin County, California, by Howard W. Derby, College of the Pacific (Box-folder 31: 329)
    16 pages; Americanization; Japanese and Chinese; Northern California
  - "The Importance of the Japanese in the Fruit and Vegetable Industry of California," by Melvin Sanguinetti, under the direction of Eliot G. Mears, 1924 Fall (Box-folder 31: 330)
    72 pages; Competition and land; Japanese; Northern and Southern California
  - "The Attitude of the College Student on the Race Question," by Catharine Ewell, prepared for Professor J. C. Almach, 1924 (Box-folder 31: 331)
    13 pages; Race consciousness, Investigations; Japanese and Chinese; Northern California
  - "The Part Played by the Japanese in the Beet Sugar Industry in California and Colorado," by N. T. Nowell, under the direction of Eliot G. Mears, 1924 Fall (Box-folder 31: 332)
    25 pages; Competition and land; Japanese; Northern and Southern California, and Colorado
  - "Cooperative Movement among Japanese Farmers in California," by Yoshio Ichikawa, Stanford University, under the direction of Eliot G. Mears, 1925 March (Box-folder 31: 333)
    72 pages; Competition and land, Communities; Japanese; Northern and Southern California
  - "The Disposition of Surplus Earnings of Orientals in America," by K. L. Emerson, under the direction of Eliot G. Mears (Box-folder 31: 334)
    23 pages; Competition and land; Japanese and Chinese; Northern and Southern California
  - "The Japanese Association of America," by Robert Sinclair Murray, under the direction of Eliot G. Mears, report submitted in fulfilment of the requirements of "Oriental Land Policies," Stanford University, 1924 Autumn (Box-folder 31: 335)
    39 pages; Communities, Americanization; Japanese; Northern California
  - "The Oriental Pioneer," by Takiji Morimoto (Box-folder 31: 336)
    28 pages; Americanization, Competition and land, Life histories; Japanese; Seattle, Washington
  - Digital copy of Box 32
  - "Interview with Professor Y. Ichihashi," Stanford University, by William C. Smith, Los Angeles (Box-folder 32: 337)
    2 pages; Race consciousness, Americanization; Japanese; Northern California
  - "How I Came to America - Junito Juarldo (Mexican)," by Olive McCall (Box-folder 32: 338)
    7 pages; Race consciousness, Americanization; Mexican; Southern California
  - "An Incident Wherein Race Prejudice Prevents the Establishment of a Church in Hollywood," by R. C. Nelson, Southern California (Box-folder 32: 339)
    6 pages; Goodwill, Race consciousness; Japanese; Southern California
  - Interview of L. R. Bowles, by William C. Smith, Hollywood, 1924 April 3 (Box-folder 32: 340)
    3 pages; Goodwill, Race consciousness; Japanese; Southern California
  - "Study of the Native Traits of the Japanese," by Lois M. Winkler, Southern California (Box-folder 32: 341)
    13 pages; Race consciousness, Heritages; Japanese; Southern California
  - "A Short Biography of Mamoru Takada, Born in 1909," by Masao Dodo, Southern California (Box-folder 32: 342)
    12 pages; Life histories, Americanization; Japanese; Southern California
  - Life history of Norio Osaki, Los Angeles (Box-folder 32: 343)
    4 pages; Life histories, Race consciousness, Americanization; Japanese; Southern California
  - "Japanese Young Men's Associations of Southern California," by Hideo Oyama (Box-folder 32: 344)
    25 pages; Communities; Japanese; Southern California
  - Life history of Masao Dodo, Southern California (Box-folder 32: 345)
    31 pages; Life histories, Heritages, Americanization, Racial traits; Japanese; Southern California
  - "Life History of T. Yoshida," by T. Yoshida (Box-folder 32: 346)
    7 pages; Life histories, Americanization; Japanese; Southern California
  - Life history of Hung Kei Lui (Box-folder 32: 347)
    8 pages; Life histories, Americanization; Chinese; Southern California
  - Life history of A. Suehiro (Box-folder 32: 348)
  - "A Social Document," by Masami Swzuki (Box-folder 32: 349)
    11 pages; Life histories, Americanization; Japanese; Southern California
  - "Life History of an Oriental Student," by H. Fukasu (Box-folder 32: 350)
  - "The Study of a Japanese Family," by H. Fukasu (Box-folder 32: 351)
    8 pages; Life histories; Japanese; Southern California
  - "My Life History," by Minoru Iino, 1926 April 12 (Box-folder 32: 352)
  - A Life History of an American-born Japanese," by Sayeki Chiko (Box-folder 32: 353)
    11 pages; Life histories, Americanization, Competition and land; Japanese; Southern California
  - "The Second Generation Japanese," by Leo Toyama (Box-folder 32: 354)
  - Proceedings of Annual Conventions of the California State Federation of Labor, 1909-1926 (Box-folder 32: 355)
    49 pages
- Minor Documents, 1907-1934 (Boxes 33-38)
  Clippings, congressional hearing transcripts, correspondence, essays, interviews, lists, memoranda, papers, personal experiences and sketches, questionnaires, remarks, reports, speeches, statements, and studies, arranged numerically by document number.
  - Digital copy of Box 33
  - Economic and social conditions of Japanese in Southern California: 102 interviews with employers of farm workers (Box-folder 33: 1)
    198 pages, with pages 53 and 54 missing; Competition and land: Agriculture; Japanese; Southern California
  - "Presbyterian Churches in California Meet Against Disallowance of Long Beach Japanese Presbyterian Church," Los Angeles Japanese - American (Box-folder 33: 2)
    1 page; Race consciousness, Communities; Japanese; Southern California
  - "The Gathering of the Pro-Japanese People at Christian Church, Long Beach," Los Angeles Japanese Daily News (Box-folder 33: 3)
    2 pages; Communities, Race consciousness; Japanese; Southern California
  - Statement, G. Bromley Oxnam, Pastor of All Nations Church, Los Angeles (Box-folder 33: 4)
    1 page; Race consciousness; Chinese; Southern California) - Missing
  - Letter to the editor (Brawley, California), "News" regarding Mexican beating his wife (Box-folder 33: 5)
    2 pages; Social disorganization; Mexican; Southern California) – Missing
  - Letter from A. W. Swanson regarding Hindu marriage (Box-folder 33: 6)
    3 pages; Intermarriage; Hindu; Southern California) - Missing
  - Shive Ram, Los Angeles Hindu (Box-folder 33: 7)
    1 page; Americanization: Naturalization; Hindu; Southern California) - Missing
  - Report, activities of Japanese fisherman, San Pedro district, 1922 (Box-folder 33: 8)
    10 pages; Japanese; Southern California) - Missing
  - Syllabus of lectures, Pacific Slope history, reference to California, by Rockwell D. Hunt (Box-folder 33: 9)
    6 pages; Southern California) - Missing
  - Report, Los Angeles Chamber of Commerce, regarding Japanese situation (Box-folder 33: 10)
  - "Caste in India," by S. D. Pandit (Box-folder 33: 11)
    2 pages; Hindu; Southern California) - Missing
  - "Removing Migration and Personal Disorganization," by K. Kimura (Box-folder 33: 12)
    3 pages; Personal, Disorganization, Life histories; Japanese; Southern California
  - "Los Angeles Pastor's Daughter Weds Japanese, Dr. Hatsuji Hara," extract from San Francisco Examiner (Box-folder 33: 13)
    2 pages; Intermarriage; Japanese; Southern California) – Missing
  - Personal sketch of Herman C. Lichtenburger, Probation Department, Los Angeles, and Frank S. Hutton, member of Schweitzer & Hutton, Los Angeles (Box-folder 33: 14)
    3 pages; Southern California) - Missing
  - The Japanese family in Southern California (Box-folder 33: 15)
    35 pages; Family; Japanese; Southern California) - Missing
  - The study of criminals among Japanese in Southern California (Box-folder 33: 16)
    15 pages; Social disorganization: Vice and crime; Japanese; Southern California) - Missing
  - Question, Long Beach Japanese mission (Box-folder 33: 17)
    3 pages; Communities, Goodwill: Religious activities, Race consciousness; Japanese; Southern California) – Missing
  - Letters relating to report of Long Beach Chamber of Commerce Committee on Japanese menace to California, Senate Committee on Immigration, Washington, D.C., 1924 March 8 (Box-folder 33: 18)
    5 pages; Population: Immigration; Japanese; Southern California
  - Experiences of an American teacher in Japan, letter to George Gleason, 1924 March 20 (Box-folder 33: 19)
    3 pages; Japanese; Southern California) - Missing
  - Harriet Buss documents (Box-folder 33: 20)
    13 pages; Chinese; Southern California) - Missing
    - Susie and JoHa, case study of Chinese invalid (1)
    - Sao Yeng, public school (2)
    - Chinese probation case (3)
    - Funeral of Chinese woman (4)
    - Bakersfield Chinese Mission (5)
  - Story by A. W. Swanson, Imperial Valley, 1924 April (Box-folder 33: 21)
    4 pages; Deliquency; Chinese; Southern California) - Missing
  - "A Japanese Wedding in America," by Elizabeth Kemp, Los Angeles, California, 1924 May 2 (Box-folder 33: 22)
  - Interview with Margaret Dooher, Americanization teacher (Box-folder 33: 23)
    2 pages; Americanization; Japanese, Korean, and Chinese; Southern California) - Missing
  - "Los Angeles Chinatown," by Clara Gilbert, 1924 June 12 (Box-folder 33: 24)
  - Interview with J. A. Knapp and A. M. Stanley, Santa Ana (Box-folder 33: 25)
    2 pages; Social disorganization; Japanese; Southern California) - Missing
  - Interview with a Chinese girl (Box-folder 33: 26)
    1 page; Americanization: Second generation; Chinese; Southern California) - Missing
  - Remarks, Reverend S., Japanese church (Box-folder 33: 27)
    1 page; Japanese; Southern California) - Missing
  - Illegal entry of Chinese (Box-folder 33: 28)
    1 page; Chinese; Southern California) - Missing
  - Interview with J. N. Hamer on his experience with different aliens (Box-folder 33: 29)
    5 pages; Southern California) - Missing
  - Interview with J. N. Hamer on business dealings with Orientals (Box-folder 33: 30)
  - "My Life History," by Takita Mitsugi, 1924 July 14 (Box-folder 33: 31)
    4 pages; Life histories; Japanese
  - Concerning the Asiatic in America (Southern California) - Missing (Box-folder 33: 32)
  - Clipping from East Side Guardian, Fred T. Beatty, editor (Box-folder 33: 33)
    1 page; Goodwill; Mexican; Southern California) - Missing
  - Impressions of personal experiences of George Gleason (Box-folder 33: 34)
  - Knight family, Upland, California (Box-folder 33: 35)
    2 pages; Intermarriage; Chinese; Southern California) - Missing
  - Japanese girl at school (Box-folder 33: 36)
    1 page; Race consciousness: prejudice; Japanese; Southern California) – Missing
  - "United States Versus Bhagat Singh Thind," extract from Supreme Court Reporter, 1923 April 1 (Box-folder 33: 37)
    6 pages; Americanization: Naturalization; Hindu; Southern California
  - "Takao Ozawa Versus United States," extract from Supreme Court Reporter, 1922 December 15 (Box-folder 33: 38)
    3 pages; Americanization: Naturalization; Japanese; Southern California
  - Thirteen years experience with Koreans in California (Box-folder 33: 39)
    2 pages; Korean; Southern California) - Missing
  - "Interview with Grace Kojima," by William C. Smith, Los Angeles, 1924 July 31 (Box-folder 33: 40)
    2 pages; Americanization; Life histories; Japanese; Southern California
  - "Asiatic Problem also Menaces Future of British Columbia," extract from Illustrated Daily News, Los Angeles, California, 1924 August 2 (Box-folder 33: 41)
    1 page; Southern California
  - Digital copy of Box 34
  - "Life History of Junro Amos Kashitani," by William C. Smith, University of Southern California, 1924 August 15 (Box-folder 34: 42)
  - "My Life History," by T. Kimoto, University of Southern California, 1924 August (Box-folder 34: 43)
  - "Family Difficulties Among the Japanese," interview with T. Kawai, by William C. Smith, Los Angeles, 1924 August 12 (Box-folder 34: 44)
    1 page; Americanization: Family problems; Japanese; Southern California
  - "Family Troubles," by K. S. Itow, Long Beach (Box-folder 34: 45)
  - "Hindus and Intermarriage," by William C. Smith, Los Angeles (Box-folder 34: 46)
    1 page; Intermarriage; Hindu; Southern California
  - "The Japanese in Long Beach," by K. S. Itow, 1924 August 2 (Box-folder 34: 47)
    1 page; Communities; Japanese; Southern California
  - "Interview with Jimmie Suzushi," American-born Japanese, by William C. Smith, 1924 August 25 (Box-folder 34: 48)
    1 page; Americanization: Second generation; Japanese; Southern California
  - Ten years experience with the Chinese on citrus ranches (Box-folder 34: 49)
    2 pages; Competition and land: Agriculture; Chinese; Southern California) - Missing
  - Survey of races in citrus district, San Bernardino County (Box-folder 34: 50)
    2 pages; Competition and land: Agriculture; Southern California) - Missing
  - "Interview with John Ando," by William C. Smith, Los Angeles, 1924 August 8 (Box-folder 34: 51)
    3 pages; Life histories, Americanization: Second generation and Vocational problems; Japanese; Southern California
  - "The Second Generation," interview with Reverend T. Kawai, by William C. Smith, Los Angeles, 1924 August 12 (Box-folder 34: 52)
    2 pages; Americanization: Second generation, Accommodation, and Vocational problems; Japanese; Southern California
  - "Interview with U----Z---" (Japanese) working for an education, difficulties of Japanese college graduate in America, by William C. Smith, 1924 August 21 (Box-folder 34: 53)
    3 pages; Life histories, Americanization: Vocational problems; Japanese; Southern California
  - "Interview with Kichi Jo," vocational problem of the college trained man, by William C. Smith, Los Angeles, 1924 August 20 (Box-folder 34: 54)
    2 pages; Life histories; Japanese; Southern California
  - "Interview with K---I---," reasons for prejudice against the Japanese, by William C. Smith, Los Angeles, California, 1924 August 19 (Box-folder 34: 55)
    2 pages; Americanization: Second generation and Vocational problems; Japanese; Southern California
  - "Interview with Frank Yura," by William C. Smith, Los Angeles, 1924 August 25 (Box-folder 34: 56)
  - "Interview with T. Kuramido," a business career, by William C. Smith, Los Angeles, California, 1924 August 22 (Box-folder 34: 57)
    1 page; Life histories, Japanese; Southern California
  - "Interview with K. Yamamoto," religion and the church, by William C. Smith, Los Angeles, 1924 August 25 (Box-folder 34: 58)
    1 page; Life histories; Japanese; Southern California
  - "Interview with Reverend M.--," Japanese minister, by William C. Smith, Los Angeles, California, 1924 August 21 (Box-folder 34: 59)
    2 pages; Life histories, Americanization: Accommodation; Japanese; Southern California
  - "Interview with Frank Nakamura," activities of the church and young people's societies, by William C. Smith, Los Angeles, 1924 August 9 (Box-folder 34: 60)
    4 pages; Americanization, Goodwill; Japanese; Southern California
  - "Interview with Tom Gubbins," by William C. Smith, Los Angeles, 1924 August 13 (Box-folder 34: 61)
    1 page; Americanization: Education; Chinese; Southern California
  - "Interview with Sun (Peter) Lee," use of Chinese language, by William C. Smith, Los Angeles, 1924 August 13 (Box-folder 34: 62)
    1 page; Third generation; Chinese; Southern California
  - "Interview with Louise Leung," by William C. Smith, Los Angeles, 1924 August 13 (Box-folder 34: 63)